Curriculum Vitae

Liam McLeod

Home Telephone: (01424) 433655, Email: <u>L McLeod95@hotmail.com</u> / <u>LiamMcLeod@bexhillcollege.ac.uk</u> http://www.dual1ty.me/

491 Bexhill Road, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 8AT

Key Skills:

- IT literate -Excellent knowledge of Microsoft Office and other specialist software suites, applications and programming: Including Adobe Photoshop, Visual Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans, Blender; Web Development in HTML, CSS (& SASS), PHP and JS (& Node) in their most recent iterations using a variety of tools, and finally application development, specifically in VB.NET, Java and JS.
- Polite, well spoken and literate.
- Base knowledge in a wide range of subjects:
 - Computer systems and servers,
 - Networking,
 - Web development (HTML, CSS, JS).
 - Database design, MySQL, SQL
 Server and PostgreSQL,

- NodeJS and PHP,
- Designing and manipulating computer graphics,
- System and network security,
- Scientific writing.

Personal Skills:

- Good communication
- Flexible
- Problem Solving

- Numeracy, Literacy and IT Skills
- Independent (but adaptable)
- Dedicated

Education and Training

2015-Current

University of Brighton, Priory Street, Hastings, TN34 1EA, United Kingdom

- 2015-18: Computer Systems with Networking (Hons) BSc

2011-2015:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

2011-12: Guitar Enrichment2013-14: Volunteer Enrichment2011-13 Level 3 Specialist National2013-15: AS Computing (B), A-Level

Diploma in IT (DMM), Psychology (D)

2006-2011:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

- GCSEs: Maths (C), English (C), Catering (C), English Literature (B), Sciences: Chemistry: (B), Physics: (B), Biology: (B) and Geography (C).
- BTECs: Level 2 Information Technology (Distinction) and Physical Education (Merit).

Employment and Experience

2010:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

Teaching Assistant for Music, English and Sciences (Work Experience)

Curriculum Vitae

2013-Current:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

- Volunteer Enrichment (2013-14)
- Volunteer in IT Faculty (2015-16) Reporting to Gary Newport

2013-Current:

Freelance Web Developer

- PMJ Groundworks (defunct)
- Examplar (Exam Paper Search Tool)
- Project X (Work in progress)

Personal Statement:

Availability: I can be available to start work as soon as required and I am able to work extra hours so long as this does not conflict with current commitments at university. Therefore, I would find employment preferable if provided with flexibility to fit around my current studies at the University of Brighton.

Leisure Interests: My leisure and recreational interests include web development, music, politics and sciences. For the most part this includes making web applications for fun, playing guitar. It is for this reason I decided to take my education further and study areas of computer science further at Brighton University, I volunteer in the IT Faculty of Bexhill College. To back this further I have previously had work experience at the Grove College as a Teaching Assistant where I assisted in the preparation, teaching and covering of lessons spanning English, the sciences, religious education and music. I enjoy a range of other activities predominantly learning, reading and live musical performances (attending and playing). This is why I decided to make the most of my opportunities at Bexhill College where I have studied four subjects and voluntarily assisted in the maintenance of the IT department resources resulting in me and why I was invited back to assist in the teaching and running of student support sessions. Due to this, I have consistently maintained a hunger and drive to learn new things especially within the fields of IT and the sciences, all of which I consider instrumental to success and important aspects to life and my development.

Personal Statement: I am a polite, well-mannered person who is keen to learn new skills and adapt to new environments. I am sociable, hardworking and determined with my work. My ideal employment would be to work within an IT based environment. However, I am happy to adapt to any environment required. I am aspirational and keen to work my way up within a business. Throughout my entire academic career I have strived to maintain a high-level of quality in my work, punctuality and my attendance, which has consistently been 100% up until my final year in college, something I know can only be an asset to any employer.

References

(Academic / Employer References)

Gary Newport

Teacher, IT Course Manager and Employer at Bexhill College (2013-16)

garynewport@bexhillcollege.ac.uk

Bexhill College

Penland Road

Bexhill-on-Sea

East Sussex

TN40 2JG

(Personal Reference)

Holly Wright

Partner

holly.wright@outlook.com 4 Catsfield Close

St Leonards-on-Sea

East Sussex

TN38 9TA